# Jon Kurinsky

Philadelphia-based &/or Remote Software Engineer github.com/krnsk0 | linkedin.com/in/krnsk0/jkurinsky+resume@fastmail.com | (847) 962-3309

#### TECHNOLOGIES & SKILLS

Highly Proficient in web application development using React; functional, declarative programming in ES6+ Javascript and Typescript; architecture for interactive web applications using a variety of state management tools and concepts; microservice development in Node; web video and audio APIs; adaptive-bitrate playback with libraries like video.js/Shaka; media processing using ffmpeg; test-first development, mob programming, and other XP-influenced techniques. Some experience with async task queues, Postgres, Python, distributed systems.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Screencastify (remote)

Software Engineer - Video Editor Team (Dec 2020 - July 2021) / Senior Software Engineer (Aug 2021 - Oct 2022): Co-led greenfield rewrite of web multitrack video editor from Angular to React that evolved into a unification of Screencastify's product suite aimed at setting business up for a new stage of growth. Co-led design of multi-source video player and effect stack based on MPEG-DASH and video.js. Led architecture for multitrack media timeline and backing data structures. Contributed to schema design (Postgres) and establishment of data access patterns using GraphQL and Hasura. Co-led design of video compositor based on HTML5 canvas and webcodecs. Built & iterated ffmpeg & node-based async media ingestion workers. Built performance dashboards for async tasks & http endpoints, leading integration into incident response practices.

Documented decisions and patterns via RFCs and ADRs to scale from a 5- to 22-person team, pairing to help others become productive in the new stack. Advocated for best practices around type safety and observability. Drove adoption of mob development, just-in-time iteration planning, and test-driven refactoring.

# IKEA (Philadelphia - remote)

**Software Engineer** (August 2020 - Dec 2020): Tech lead for cross-functional SEO & web perf team. Built Puppeteer-based synthetic-user performance testing tool to uncover load time improvements for IKEA's microfrontends-based global ecommerce platform; received an "IKEA Innovator" award for this work. Designed & ran web-performance A/B tests using this and other tools.

### Comcast (Philadelphia - remote)

Engineer 2, Software Development (October 2019 - July 2020): Lead UI dev for greenfield React-based customer-facing payments app with millions of users. 70/30 split between code and planning/work breakdown. Co-designed a React-based microfrontends architecture and associated tooling; co-led effort to drive adoption of CI/CD. Organized and presented trainings on Node as part of effort to unify department around a shared stack.

## <u>Fullstack Academy</u> (Chicago)

Teaching Fellow (June 2019 - September 2019): Mentored & taught students at 13-week web dev bootcamp; led algorithm exercises; conducted technical interviews with prospective students.

## Havmarket Books / Center for Economic Research and Social Change (Chicago)

Logistics & Operations Manager (September 2011 - November 2018): Self-taught Python to build tools for automating operations workflows for a nonprofit publisher through period of 400% growth in order volume, integrating web scrapers, APIs, shipping hardware, and data viz tools. Co-stakeholder for agency-led rewrite of company website. Content manager / audio editor for www.wearemany.org; automated audio post-production and content management workflows using Python, SoX, boto3.

### **EDUCATION**

# Fullstack Academy (January 2019 - May 2019)

13-week rigorous immersive development bootcamp teaching industry-standard professional practices and tooling for modern front- and back-end web development using a Javascript-based stack.

### University of Chicago (September 2005 - June 2009)

BA in philosophy; focus on logic & formal semantics. Multiple awards for academic papers & contributions to undergraduate academic life.